changents.com 2010-05-10

# Website Privacy Policy - Changents

## Privacy Policy

July 2007

As an ethical company, we take the privacy of our users very seriously. We provide this Privacy Policy because you have a right to know what information we collect about you, how it is protected and used, and the circumstances under which it may be disclosed. Please read this Privacy Policy to learn more about how we treat personally identifiable information. If you have comments, suggestions, questions, or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us via email at help@changents.com. 

_What This Privacy Policy Covers_

This Privacy Policy covers Changents' treatment of personally identifiable information that we obtain when you visit our website or become a registered user of the Changents Service. We regard personally identifiable information as information that someone can use to identify or contact you in person, such as your real name, telephone number, birth date, email address, or physical mailing address. Information that we use internally to identify you as a registered user in our system, such as your selected username, is not considered personally identifiable information. 

_What This Privacy Policy Does Not Cover_

This Privacy Policy does not cover the privacy practices of third parties that we do not own or control, such as but not limited to our partners, vendors and advertisers. In addition, we may provide links to other services and other sites that may interest you. All of these sites operate independently of the Changents Service and may have their own privacy or security practices. For your best online experience, we encourage you to review their policies before submitting any personal information to them. 

#### INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

_Required Registration Information_

During the registration process, we collect required information about you including but not necessarily limited to your name, username, password, email address, mobile phone number, date of birth, gender, country of residence, postal code and action area (i.e. social or environmental interest areas). 

_Optional Registration Information_

You can choose to provide us with additional optional information about yourself in your registered user profile such as a photo of yourself, an avatar or other information as may be requested from time to time. 

_Access To Your Personal Information_

In general, we make it easy for you to view your profile and the personally identifiable information that we have collected from you in your password protected personal user account, where you can cancel add and edit information or cancel your account. 

_Information Submitted During A Transaction_

To the extent commerce offerings are made available to you on the Changents Service, we may collect information including your name, shipping and billing address(es), credit card information and other relevant data to process your payment transaction. 

#### INFORMATION WE DO NOT COLLECT 

_Children_

As explained further in our Terms of Service, currently available at www.changents.com/about/terms, you must be 18 years of age or older to use the Changents Service. Therefore, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information about children. If you believe that we have information from or about anyone under 13 years of age, please notify us immediately by email at help@changents.com. 

_Social Security Number_

We do not ask or require your Social Security Number to use or access any part of the Changents Service. No one representing Changents will ever ask for your Social Security Number. If at any time you receive an e-mail requesting such information from someone purporting to represent the Company or the Changents Service, please notify us immediately. 

#### INFORMATION WE TRACK 

_Log Files_

We gather certain information about your actions on the Changents Service and automatically store it in our database and web server log files. This information may include but is not limited to your user name, unique IDs appended to URLs that you use in connection with the Changents Service, internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), site entry/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to facilitate custom features such as the Ripple and to deliver content or advertising that may be of interest to you based on your preferences and user behavior on the Changents Service. In addition, this data helps us improve our site, analyze trends, administer the site, understand the interests of our user base as a whole, select appropriate partners and sell good corporate citizen advertising to support the Changents Service. We also collect aggregate information which is data about a group or category of services or users from which individual user identities have been removed, and therefore does not include your personally identifiable information. 

_Cookies_

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. It can also help us understand how our site visitors click to our site, what pages they view during their visit, responses tied to send-to-a-friend and other Ripple-related actions, how much time they spend with certain content experiences, etc. Similar to many websites, we store an encrypted cookie on your computer so we can remember you when you come back to our website. Cookies also allow us to track and understand the interests of our users to enhance the overall experience on our site. You can set your web browser software to disable cookies. To do so, please refer to the help section of your specific browser for more information about how to manage or disable cookies. If you disable cookies, you may still view our site, but some areas of the Changents Service may not work as intended. Some of our business partners and advertisers may also use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies, and, as noted above, this privacy policy does not govern the use of cookies by our business partners, vendors or advertisers. 

#### HOW INFORMATION IS USED 

_In Company Communications_

We use emails and/or prominent notifications on our website as our primary means to inform our registered users of important service and promotional announcements. 

_System-related Announcements_

We use your email address to deliver important system-related announcements. Examples of system-related announcements include but are not limited to: email verification during registration, requests for password reset, important security or server maintenance updates, or policy changes. These service-related announcements are considered a fundamental part of the Changents Service, and registered users cannot opt-out of these email announcements. 

_Promotional Announcements_

In order to improve the experience for our registered users, we will offer you the ability to sign up for optional communications, such as email updates about the Changents Service, or invitations. These communications are enhancements to the Changents Service and are entirely optional. We will ask for your consent before sending you promotional communications, and will make it easy for you to unsubscribe from these communications, either through emails or though your password protected personal user account. 

Send-To-A-Friend Features 

If you choose to use our send-to-a-friend features on the Changents Service, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend an email inviting him or her to visit the site. 

_Nominate a Change Agent_

If you choose to nominate a private individual as a change agent on the Changents Service, we will ask you for your nominee’s name and email address. We will automatically notify your nominee of the nomination and invite him or her to visit the site. 

_The Ripple_

The Ripple, a signature feature of Changents is a technology that will dynamically track and graphically represent the positive impact of Internet-based actions taken by Changents registered users as those actions spread virally from person to person, affecting the actions of others down the line. Therefore, certain actions that you may take on the Changents Service, such as but not limited to invite a friend, forward content, nominate a change agent, recommend an action pack and the like will be trackable and viewable within the My Ripple feature of other users. Similarly, other users that take actions as a result of a Ripple that you initiate within the Changents Service will be viewable in your My Ripple view. Changents will only display non-personally identifiable information in connection with the display of user actions in the My Ripple view. 

_Identification Of Authors By Username_

The Changents website offers opportunities for registered users to vote and comment on content found on this website, engage in dialogue, share information, and submit original content such as videos, photos and other media. This means that we depend on the contributions and actions of our registered users to improve the quality of the Changents Service experience. When you make a contribution to the Changents Service (such as uploading a video), you may be identified by your username as the author of that contribution both on our website and on the websites of third parties such as Veoh to whom we distribute your content. In these circumstances, we will only identify you by your username. Other than the username which can be entirely made up, in using the Changents Service, you are not required to provide or publicize any personally identifiable information in connection with your contributions and actions on our website or any third party website with whom we may distribute your contribution. 

_Public Profile_

As the Changents Service evolves, we may create a public member profile based on your username. You have the option to include personally identifiable information in your public profile, but you are not required to do so. You can easily add, edit, and delete information in your public member profile from your password protected personal user account. 

_Site Statistics_

As noted above, we may use information collected from our web log files to calculate and publish anonymous, non-personally identifiable, aggregate statistics about how users of the Changents Service access the website. For example, we may track and publish the total number of users who have viewed a particular web page. We publish this data in aggregate form only, and do not tie it to any personally identifiable information. 

#### HOW INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED AND DISCLOSED 

_Public Messages on Changents_

Some of our features allow you to communicate with other users by posting public messages (such as when you make comments on a blog post or message board). Please be aware that what you write in these public messages can be viewed, collected or used by anyone who visits our website. We are not responsible for any personally identifiable information that you submit or permit others to submit through public messages. 

_Sharing, Renting, And Selling Information We Collect_

Occasionally we share anonymous, non-personally identifiable, aggregate information about our user base with partners, vendors or advertisers. We do not tie this shared or published data to personally identifiable information. To the extent that we offer registered users the opportunity to opt-in to receiving information from socially responsible organizations, we may make a list of such users available to these organizations. If at any time you no longer want to receive this information from third parties, we will make available to you a means to opt out on your password protected personal account or you can email us at help@changents.com. 

_Linked Services_

In some cases, we allow you to access or link to other web services through our website. In all of these cases, third parties to whom we link may choose to collect your personal information as they deem appropriate. As noted above, we are not responsible for or in control of how third parties collect, use, or disclose your information obtained through these linked services. We encourage you to be aware when you are using these third party services and, for your best online experience, we encourage you to review their policies before submitting any personal information to them. 

_Legal Requirements_

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website. 

_Acquisition Or Other Transfer_

If our Company is acquired, all of our assets, including user information, may be transferred to the acquiring company. At that time, your user account information, including personally identifiable information, may become subject to the acquiring company's privacy policy. In addition, in the event that we must liquidate our assets due to bankruptcy or other event, we will consider our registered user information, including personally identifiable information, as a unique asset subject to sale or other transfer. Before we transfer your information under any of these scenarios, we will notify you either by email or by posting a notice on our site. 

#### HOW INFORMATION IS KEPT SECURE 

_Security of Account Information_

Your user account information is password-protected. We will not share your password with anyone. Please do not share your password with anyone, and remember to change your password from time to time, to keep your account information secure. 

_Network Security_

We have implemented a variety of industry standard encryption and security technologies and procedures to protect information, including your personal information, stored in our computer systems from unauthorized access. Please be aware that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, thus we strive to use industry standard means to protect your personal information, but we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

_Management Procedures_

We also maintain standard physical and electronic procedural safeguards that limit access to your personally identifiable information to our employees (or independent contractors working on our behalf and under confidentiality agreements) who, through the course of standard business activities, need to access your personally identifiable information. 

#### YOUR PERSONAL CHOICES 

_Sharing Information with Other Registered Users_

To the extent that we offer public profiles for registered users, you are able to control what personally identifiable information about you is shared with other users in your public member profile and what information you choose to keep private. You will be able to view, add, edit and delete information in your public member profile from your password protected personal user account provided that all required fields are compete. 

_Receiving Communications_

If you subscribe to any optional promotional communications, you will be able to unsubscribe from them through your password protected personal user account or through the emails we send to you. 

_Editing, Updating or Deleting Member Profile Information_

You can view personally identifiable information we have collected from you in your password protected personal user account where you can add, edit or delete information provided that all required fields are complete. You may also delete your registered user account at any time. 

#### FOR OUR CANADIAN REGISTERED USERS 

Canadian citizens, except under circumstances defined by law, are entitled to access their own personally identifiable information collected by the Changents Service by writing to Changents, P.O. Box 518, Durham, New Hampshire 03824. We may ask you to pay an administrative fee for accessing or copying your information, but will inform you of the anticipated charges and confirm that you want us to proceed before processing your request. If you believe that the personally identifiable information about you that we have collected is incomplete or inaccurate, we will correct the information upon verification of the omission or error and the identity of the person requesting the change. If you would like to access, correct or have us provide you additional information about or investigate any matters in relation to your personally identifiable information, please contact us at the address provided above. 

#### NOTICE FOR USERS OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES 

You should be aware that the United States and other countries have not harmonized their privacy regulations. Because the Changents Service operates from the United States, we have written our Privacy Policy to satisfy United States regulations. By using the Changents Service, you agree to the level of privacy protection set out in our Privacy Policy. 

#### UPDATES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY 

Our service is evolving and developing. From time to time, we will review and make changes to our Privacy Policy. In the event of a material change to this Privacy Policy that affects how we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you by email. Ordinary course of business changes to the Privacy Policy may be made from time to time without notice. The most recent version of our Privacy Policy is always available from a link on our homepage. We encourage you to visit this site frequently to stay up to date on our current policy.
